# **Luke Vickers**

London | +44 7441 118823 | vickerslu@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Website

#### **SUMMARY**

First-Class Computer Science graduate backed by six years of diverse support experience, including IT support/infrastructure engineering. Energetic self-starter, problem-solver, and team player with a professional demeanor and well-rounded technical skills. Continuous learner with a strong ability to quickly grasp new concepts, seeking to leverage insights gained from professional experience and personal cloud projects to transition into a cloud-focused role.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# J. Rothschild Capital Management

March 2024 - Present

IT Support/Infrastructure Engineer

- Maintaining onsite IT infrastructure for a £3 billion financial investment trust within a small team of 3, reporting directly to the Infrastructure Manager and IT Director.
- Administering user accounts, mailboxes, groups, and permissions across the hybrid on-premises and 365 environment.
- Handling all support tickets from over 70 colleagues, including C-suite executives and VIP's, ensuring efficient and professional resolution of technical issues.
- Implemented Single Sign-On (SSO) within Entra ID for various third-party applications to enhance security and user experience, ensuring smooth rollout with minimal downtime.
- Managed an end-to-end printer replacement project for 5 departments, achieving seamless network integration with zero downtime.
- Implemented a company-wide ticketing system, significantly streamlining IT support processes and enhancing user experience.
- Maintaining robust backup and disaster recovery solutions to safeguard critical data.

# **eduthing** *Onsite IT Support Engineer*

October 2023 - March 2024

 Managed the IT in a dynamic, high-pressure environment, maintaining strong working relationships with key stakeholders to strategically align IT solutions with the institution's goals.

- Delivered comprehensive technical support to staff through remote assistance, phone support, and in-person interactions, promptly addressing hardware and software issues to minimise disruptions to the learning environment.
- Utilised ticketing software to exceed Service Level Agreements (SLAs), ensuring the swift resolution of over 50 weekly IT support tickets while consistently upholding client satisfaction benchmarks.
- Wrote scripts to automate common repetitive tasks using Python and PowerShell, eliminating manual workload.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to efficiently escalate and resolve complex issues, contributing to a streamlined and responsive IT support ecosystem.

#### **Tesco**

# September 2018 - October 2023

Customer Support and Sales

- Acted as the initial point of contact for customers, providing product information, and offering assistance, whilst resolving customer concerns promptly, maintaining a 95% customer satisfaction rate and preserving the store's positive reputation.
- Cultivated lasting relationships with customers through strong communication skills, establishing a loyal customer base and contributing to an increase in repeat business.
- Received over 20 "Wow" comments in recognition of outstanding dedication to customer service.
- Collaborated with a diverse team to achieve departmental goals, fostering a positive and cooperative work environment.

#### **EDUCATION**

## BSc (Hons) Computer Science | First Class

2019 - 2022

Queen Mary University of London

Modules included cloud computing, security engineering, distributed systems, operating systems, computer systems and networks, wb technology, internet protocols.

# A-Levels in Computer Science, Photography and Graphic Design | AA\*B

2017 - 2019

Barking Abbey Sixth Form

## **PROJECTS**

## Cloud-Hosted Resume (Azure) | www.vickers.work | Github

2024

- Deployed HTML, CSS and Javascript files to Azure Blob Storage, and hosted them on the Azure CDN.
- Registered a custom domain and set up DNS to point to an Azure Endpoint using CNAME records. Additionally, set up HTTPS on the custom domain to ensure secure delivery with SSL.
- Utilised serverless Azure Functions to connect to a CosmosDB to track, update and display visitor count (Python).
- Utilised Identity and Access Management (IAM) to configure Role-Based Access Control (RBAC), ensuring that the Azure Function was granted the least privilege necessary to interact with CosmosDB.
- Configured Git for source control and Implemented CI/CD with GitHub Actions to automate deployment.

## Top-down 2D Shooter Video Game (Unity, C#) | Github

2023

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

## **BTTC: Bloomberg Technical Training Certification**

**July 2024** 

Qualified to install and support Bloomberg Terminals

#### **ADDITIONAL**

- Cloud Platforms: Microsoft Azure, 365 Admin, Google Cloud Platform
- **Virtualisation:** VMWare's vCenter/vSphere
- Networking and Security: Cisco routing, switching, VLANs, Palo Alto Firewalls, Cortex XDR
- Protocols and Security: TCP/IP, RDP, SSH, DNS, DHCP, HTTP
- **Operating Systems:** Windows (including Windows Server)
- Identity Governance/Administration: Active Directory, Group Policy, Entra ID (formerly Azure AD), 365 Admin, Google Admin
- Programming Languages: Python, Java, Powershell, C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL
- Backup/Disaster Recovery: Veeam
- Hardware: Motherboards, CPUs, RAM, SSDs/HDDs, PSUs, Monitors, Cabling, VoIP Phones, Printers, etc.
- **Support Ticketing Systems**: Halo PSA, Jitbit